<resources>
    <string name="app_name">MotoGP Riders</string>

    <array name="riderImages">
        <item>@drawable/marquest</item>
        <item>@drawable/rossi</item>
        <item>@drawable/dovisiozo</item>
        <item>@drawable/vinales</item>
        <item>@drawable/bradl</item>
        <item>@drawable/fabio</item>
        <item>@drawable/iannone</item>
        <item>@drawable/karel</item>
        <item>@drawable/zarco</item>
        <item>@drawable/franco</item>
    </array>

    <string-array name="riderDescription">
        <item>Marc Marquez is the youngest ever six-time World Champion after taking his most recent – and fourth –
            premier class crown in 2017. On the podium in his rookie 125 campaign in 2008, Marquez won that crown in
            2010 before moving up to Moto2™ for 2011. After a tough start, the rider from Cervera went on an incredible
            winning spree and had closed the gap to Championship leader Stefan Bradl to a handful of points, before a
            crash in practice for the Malaysian GP saw Marquez forced to cede the fight and miss the two remaining races
            of the year. Problems with his vision in the off season saw surgery then finally fix the problem, and
            despite the shortened preparation for 2012 the Spaniard took the crown in stunning style by the Australian
            GP. Replacing outgoing Casey Stoner in 2013 at the Repsol Honda Team, Marquez won his second ever MotoGP™
            race and incredibly took the Championship in his rookie year. Then beginning 2014 with 10 wins in a row,
            Marquez won that crown in Motegi to successfully defend the title. Before 2015 proved more difficult with
            some mistakes and too many DNFs. Losing out to Jorge Lorenzo and Valentino Rossi, Marquez began 2016 with a
            point to prove and took another incredible Championship title – redesigning his mentality and thinking about
            the long game as he put consistency at the top of the agenda. The reigning Champion then fought down to the
            wire against Andrea Dovizioso for the 2017 crown, with everything going down to the final round and Marquez
            - despite an incredible moment into Turn 1 - keeping it on the podium to break another record and take
            another title. He began 2018 as the reigning Champion once more and went on to make more history, taking
            nine wins and wrapping up the title in Japan - becoming the youngest ever seven-time World Champion. 2019
            sees the Spaniard aiming for eight.
        </item>
        <item>Valentino Rossi is a 9-time World Champion and 2018 will be his 23rd season in the World Championship. The
            only rider in history to win 125, 250, 500 and MotoGP™ World Championships, Rossi dominated MotoGP™ with
            first Honda and then Yamaha, taking the crown five times in a row until Nicky Hayden won the title in 2006.
            Back on top in 2008 and 2009, the Italian was then beaten to the crown by teammate Jorge Lorenzo in 2010 and
            left to join the factory Ducati Team. After three podiums over a tough two seasons, the rider from Tavullia
            was back at Yamaha for 2013 and took his first win in three years in Assen. Runner up in the title in 2014,
            Rossi then fought for his tenth crown in 2015 but was beaten in the final race by Lorenzo once again. 2016
            has seen more pole positions, podiums and race wins and saw the Italian runner up once again; remaining with
            Movistar Yamaha MotoGP for 2017 with new teammate Maverick Viñales. Another win, at the Dutch GP at the TT
            Circuit Assen, was the jewel in another successful season – but struggles for the team with low grip and a
            broken leg sustained in training just before Misano put a damper on the latter half of the year. Rossi
            impressed to come back from his injury after only three weeks, however, and took another podium before the
            end of the year, coming second in the awesome showdown at Phillip Island. For 2018, the Italian remained
            with Yamaha and took another top three overall in the standings, but Rossi didn\'t stand on the top step in
            2018. He\'ll be gunning to change that this season and pushing Yamaha Factory Racing to make some gains on
            their rivals and close the gap.
        </item>
        <item>Taking his second MotoGP™ win in Sepang in 2016, 2004 125 World Champion Andrea Dovizioso has been in
            MotoGP™ since an incredible rookie season in 2008, where he was top Independent Team rider and fifth
            overall. His first victory came at Donington in 2009 when riding for Repsol Honda, before the Italian moved
            to the Ducati Team following a stint with Monster Yamaha Tech 3. A key part of Ducati’s journey back to the
            top, ‘DesmoDovi’ is one of the hardest to overtake on the brakes – and one of the cleanest competitors in
            battle. After long seasons of hard work saw the bike more and more competitive and a consistent frontrunner,
            2017 saw the Italian challenge for the World Championship down to the wire in Valencia after a stunning six
            wins across the season. For 2018, he hit the ground running to win the season opener, endured some harder
            races and then came back swinging - ending the year runner up once again. The goal for 2019? Go one better.
        </item>
        <item>2013 Moto3™ World Champion Maverick Viñales took the lightweight title in the CEV in 2010, as well as the
            European 125 Championship the following year, and debuted in the 125 World Championship in 2011. He won four
            races in his rookie year – third in the Championship and Rookie of the Year – and then took that title in
            2013. As a Moto2™ rookie in 2014, Viñales was again Rookie of the Year and won four races – moving up to
            MotoGP™ the year after with Team Suzuki Ecstar. Another Rookie of the Year trophy followed, before the
            Spaniard then took Suzuki’s first race win since 2007 – and his maiden MotoGP™ win – at the British GP in
            2016. For 2017, Viñales moved to Movistar Yamaha MotoGP to partner none other than Italian legend Valentino
            Rossi. After dominating pre-season testing, the Yamaha rider won the first two races of the year and the
            French GP, but the Movistar Yamaha team’s struggles with low grip then saw a more difficult latter half of
            the season. Viñales came third overall, and the struggles continued into 2018. It was the Spaniard who
            brought Yamaha\'s longest losing streak to an end, however, as he won in Australia - and in 2019 he\'ll be
            aiming to take the Iwata marque back into the hunt for victory every weekend. He\'ll also be changing number
            from 25 to 12.
        </item>
        <item>Son of former 250 rider Helmut Bradl, Stefan started out in the World Championship in 2006 in the 125
            class, his breakthrough season coming in 2008 when he won two races and placed fourth overall. In 2010 he
            stepped into the new Moto2™ category, ending the year ninth in the standings with an impressive victory at
            Estoril. Bradl was confirmed as the 2011 Moto2™ World Champion at the final round of the season in Valencia,
            beating Marc Marquez to the title. He joined the LCR Team aboard a Honda in 2012 for his first venture in
            the MotoGP™ class, which saw him win the Rookie of the Year title after some strong performances. The next
            year, Bradl finished on the podium from a career-first pole position at Laguna Seca, but his season ended
            early after he broke an ankle in Malaysia. In 2014 he did not return to the podium and in 2015 he enjoyed a
            new challenge with Forward Racing on the Forward Yamaha. Bradl experienced a difficult start to the season,
            only managing to finish in the points twice in the first nine races, with a best-placed finish of eighth at
            the Catalan GP. After nine races, Bradl was released from his contract at Forward Racing and took on a new
            challenge by joining the Factory Aprilia Racing Team Gresini for the second half of the season. Bradl would
            stay with Aprilia in 2016 as they brought in an all new prototype machine.
        </item>
        <item>Frenchman Fabio Quartararo got his start in motorcycle racing at the age of four, moving to Spain to
            develop his career and proclaimed national champion in the 70, 80 and 125 categories. In 2013 he won the FIM
            CEV Repsol Moto3™ championship and went on to win the same title again in 2014. The previous rule against
            participating in the Moto3™ World Championship until the age of 16 had been repealed for the winner of the
            then-national crown, so for 2015 - aged just 15 - Quartararo joined teammate Jorge Navarro in the Estrella
            Galicia 0,0 Honda team. Impressing from the start, Quartararo was on the podium in just his second race. He
            repeated that in Assen after claiming pole at both Jerez and Le Mans, but unfortunately a late season ankle
            injury halted his progress. For 2016 he moved to the Leopard Racing team with KTM machinery, and then moved
            up to Moto2™ in 2017 with Paginas Amarillas HP40. After some impressive showings of pace, Quartararo moved
            to Speed Up for his sophomore season in the intermediate class and took his first win - and pole - at the
            Circuit de Barcelona-Catalunya. He\'s now moving up to the premier class with Petronas Yamaha SRT, alongside
            more experienced teammate Franco Morbidelli.
        </item>
        <item>Andrea Iannone debuted in the 125 World Championship in 2005, taking his first win of the class in 2008.
            More victories prefaced the Italian’s move to Moto2™ for 2010, finishing an impressive third in his first
            and second seasons. For 2012 the ‘Maniac’ was once again a frontrunner and battled Marc Marquez and Pol
            Espargaró in the intermediate class, before moving up to MotoGP™ in 2013 with Pramac Racing Team. After
            consistent results in his rookie year, Iannone joined the factory Ducati Team for two years, taking his
            first win at the Austrian GP in 2016 and showcasing his aggressive on-track battles. The Italian moved to
            Team Suzuki Ecstar for 2017 and, after a tough start, began to gain some traction towards the end of the
            year – before hitting the ground running with the Hamamatsu factory in 2018 and taking some impressive
            podiums. Now he moves to Aprilia Racing Team Gresini to begin a new chapter in 2019.
        </item>
        <item>Karel Abraham began racing the 125cc World Championship in 2005 before moving up the ranks into the
            intermediate class. He scored two podiums during his rookie year of Moto2™ in 2010, a third placing at the
            Twin Ring Motegi followed quite soon after by his first Grand Prix victory at the season-closer in Valencia.
            Advancing into the MotoGP™ class the following season, Abraham has since ridden Ducati, ART and Honda
            machinery, and proved a consistent points-scorer. After recovering from injury in 2015, Abraham returned to
            MotoGP™ following a year in WorldSBK and spent a second season in the premier class with the Angel Nieto
            Team in 2018. In 2019 he moves to Reale Avintia Racing.
        </item>
        <item>Former Red Bull Rookies Cup winner Johann Zarco made the jump into the 125 World Championship in 2009,
            becoming runner-up to the title in 2011 with Aki Ajo’s team before transitioning to Moto2™. Over the next
            three years, he achieved six podiums in the intermediate class before moving back to partner Ajo in his
            Moto2™ team, winning the Championship in 2015 and becoming the first man to successfully defend the Moto2™
            crown since its introduction in 2010 when he took the honours again in 2016. The first Frenchman to win more
            than one World Championship, Zarco moved into MotoGP™ for 2017 and made an impressive debut with three
            podiums and two pole positions in his rookie year. He stayed with Monster Yamaha Tech 3 in 2018 and took
            more podiums, ending the season as top Independent Team rider. In 2019 he moves to Red Bull KTM Factory
            Racing to become part of the Austrian factory\'s assault on the premier class.
        </item>
        <item>Born in Rome and now living in the motorsport-rich Tavullia, Franco Morbidelli took the Superstock 600
            title in 2013 alongside World Championship wildcard outings in Moto2™ at Misano, Motegi and Valencia. He
            went on to sign with Italtrans Racing Team for a full campaign in 2014 and continued with them in 2015,
            making his podium debut in Indianapolis. Unfortunately a broken leg sustained during a motocross training
            session saw him miss several races after Brno, with Morbidelli returning to finish the season but far from
            fully fit. For 2016 he signed with the highly successful Estrella Galicia 0,0 Marc VDS team and took an
            incredible run of podium finishes, ending the year just outside the top three in the title fight after an
            impressive campaign. For 2017, Morbidelli stayed with EG0,0 Marc VDS and came out swinging to take the first
            three wins of the year - in the lead in the standings during the entire season and taking the title at the
            Malaysian GP...from STK600 to World Champion in four years. He moved into the premier class within the same
            EG 0,0 Marc VDS team in 2018 and took the Rookie of the Year honours, and for 2019 moves team and machinery
            as he lines up with Petronas Yamaha SRT.
        </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="riderName">
        <item>Marc Marquest</item>
        <item>Valentino Rossi</item>
        <item>Andrea Dovisiozo</item>
        <item>Maveric Vinales</item>
        <item>Stefan Bradl</item>
        <item>Fabio Quartararo</item>
        <item>Andrea Iannone</item>
        <item>Karel Abraham</item>
        <item>Johann Zarco</item>
        <item>Franco Morbidelli</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="riderTeam">
        <item>Repsol Honda Team</item>
        <item>Monster Energy Yamaha</item>
        <item>Ducati Team</item>
        <item>Monster Energy Yamaha</item>
        <item>Repsol Honda</item>
        <item>Petronas Yamaha</item>
        <item>Aprilia Racing</item>
        <item>Reale Avintia Racing</item>
        <item>Red Bull KTM</item>
        <item>Petronas Yamaha</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>
